Gyro Zeppeli wins!
We have our first race
leader on the Steel Ball Run!
He did it!
Gyro came in first.
The secret to his victory was...
the power of the spin!
Fine work today, Valkyrie.
I have to win this race, no matter
the cost, so give it your all.
No pressure, though, right?
Gyro Zeppeli.
That man does not volunteer
details of his past.
According to authorities, he's new here.
He came to America from Genoa,
Italy this last May, Mr.
Steele.
Hmm?
So he's a foreigner?
Yes, sir.
He arrived on a ship registered to
a certain Royal European bloodline.
Mr. Steele!
The deliberation results are in!
I don't get it.
This can't be happening!
Don't tell me my 1 in 5 billion
luck is coming gone already, man!
How could First Place have
eluded me? Damn it all!
I am D .O. Brando!
Would anyone like some food?
Our racers eat for free!
He looks like the registration clerk.
Is it a different guy?
I'll take it.
Just the way you called it.
You have my congratulations for now.
Thanks for that, kid.
But don't be too gracious in defeat,
unless you're throwing in the towel.
To one and all, I laud your patience.
The first stage rankings
will now be unveiled.
After much careful deliberation,
the winner of the first leg?
is the possessor of Saddlecloth 990!
It's Sandman!
Thank
you
so
much
for
watching.
Let's go.
I will explain all.
Based on observations
from our hot air balloon,
Gyro Zeppeli used a weapon
to obstruct the path ahead.
It was at the end of the downhill
slope just before the final turn.
The end of the slope?
Oh, then.
As a result,
Gyro will be demoted 20 places
in this first leg of the race,
and the racers behind him
will move up accordingly.
So, Dio's second, huh?
And Poco Loco got third.
Yeah, but the big news here is
that Mountain Tim came in fourth.
He squeezed his horse's nose
in there right at the end.
Slow Dancer, what are you doing?
Mountain Tim?
A cowboy forged in the
crucible of the West.
I'd heard the rumors, of course?
That all horses bow their
heads in respect to him!
when he passes by.
Congratulations, Mr.
Steel, on a successful first stage.
Much obliged.
When will the next one commence?
Something you wish to get
off your chest, Zeppelin?
Normally you'd be disqualified for
that stunt you pulled back there.
No, sir, no complaints.
No point complaining about the past.
It's not like I can
take it back now, right?
Hmm.
Guess I came here, so I can head
into tomorrow on a fresh slate.
Enjoy your champagne.
I know I will.
Hey, what do you mean?
Whoa!
Huh?
What in the...
What is the meaning of this?
I paid cop's dollar to
ship this into France!
Excuse me, sir.
Hmm?
Problem, Sheriff?
May I have a moment of your time?
We should speak in private.
Is it wrong that made me feel better?
Are you going to nip at my heels in the
second stage of the race, Johnny Joe Star?
Well, yeah.
Right up until I breeze past you.
Very well.
Here is your second lesson.
Never let your muscles
in on the plan. Ever.
Observe.
The more pressure you apply when
grabbing your wrist with your free hand,
the more your muscles want to react
to that force by shaking it off.
The body instinctively
tries to protect itself
because the muscles sense what's going on.
That's how it is with living bodies.
The steel ball's spin keeps them
in the dark, so keep it skin deep.
That way, the muscles have no
idea something strange is afoot.
Keep it skin-deep, huh?
That's your advice?
Give it a whirl, if you're up for it.
That champagne cork in your hand has
some pretty good spin going already.
And that's how you get off the horse.
Their muscles didn't even notice it.
That was the reverse of the spin
for when I got on the horse!
Keep the muscles in the dark.
It's not the steel ball itself,
but the power of spin that's key.
Stage two of the race crosses
the desert, Johnny Joestar.
Over 700 miles in total.
It's going to be tough.
I say we form an alliance.
What better way to finish the
stage than in first and second?
I'll be the one in first place, though.
What?
What the hell am I looking at?
Pretty obvious, ain't it?
You're looking at the scene
of a brutal murder, sir.
A massacre carried out
during your steel ball run.
Over 3,000 racers took
part in that first leg of
the race and not a damn
one of them saw anything.
You think it was a jockey?
But what motive would they have to...
I can think of a cool 50 million of them.
For that much money,
nothing's off the table.
All participants are
suspects at this juncture,
and we must assume there
will be more victims.
Do you intend to halt the race to
allow for a full investigation?
No!
The steel ball run is bigger
than any one man's ambitions now!
I figured as much.
Please, dear.
Be careful.
The scent of these blooms
is said to calm the soul.
I would be honored if
you would accept them.
I'm sure you're
worried sick
for your beloved husband.
Man, what life wouldn't be.
I'll sort this out finer than frog hair.
That's mountain.
Tim is it not?
What's he doing here?
I brought him out to
track down the killer.
It's right in his wheelhouses.
I'm sure you know?
Track down the killer?
But he's a member of the race.
All the more reason to you.
Next, what better motivation
to catch the culprit quick?
I'm touched by your concern. Mr.
Steel, I'm appointing Mountain Tim
as deputy sheriff in this matter.
If and that meets with
your approval, of course.
A hell of a way to go.
How am I supposed to win the race in peace,
knowing it contained so vile a villain?
I got a lot of friends in the race and
I'll be damned if I let them get butchered.
If I have to pick a set of prints
to start tracking, it's this one!
You gotta run a horse hard
to get prints like this.
And there's a mountain-shaped ship
in the middle of this horseshoe?
What of it?
Bet you this horse was riled up,
probably from seeing all that carnage.
But the rider kept him under
control during the murder.
They know the terrain a
bottle near the victims.
Something solid inside there
is that a close button.
Does it have something to
do with how they met their
grizzly end it came off of
one of the victims jeans?
Why would the button be off though, and
how did it end up inside that bottle?
In any case,
by the time our killer
got close enough that
these poor unfortunates
took stock of them,
it was too late.
Five minutes until the starting gun.
The second stage is Herculean,
covering some 750 miles in total.
It will be the work of
two weeks, give or take.
The racers will brave the deserts of Arizona,
reaching the goal in Monument Valley.
So long as they pass through
our mandated checkpoint,
they are free to choose their
own routes along the way.
Gyro,
the paper says Sandman
is the favorite to win
this betting and he's
the odds on favorite.
What do you think? Not me.
There's no accounting for taste.
Clearly they're missing out.
Did you know I'm the sixth most popular?
It says here that you're ninth.
Pearls before swine.
They wouldn't know talent.
if I spun it up their ass.
Not that I care, of course.
See Mountain Tim over there?
He's popular with the fans
and favored to win too.
Easy there, boy.
He's got a weird hat.
Just look, I kind of want to trample it.
Bearing it if I'm being completely on it.
Mountain Tim is a bonafide cowboy.
Short stages aren't
supposed to be his strength!
but he still caught up with
me without my noticing it.
and passed me right at the finish line.
Even with that hat of
his, you didn't see him?
Kind of beggar's belief.
Looking over a map of the area, I think our
biggest challenge will be finding water.
All 26 members of a cavalry
unit died out there in 1875.
It wasn't a battle or an
accident that did them in.
A watering hole there for some reason.
They searched in vain for
another source of hydration.
The burning sun beating
the life out of them.
But it was no use.
They all roasted to death.
Magic.
The map says there's water here,
30 miles out from where we start?
and the only one that day.
If we can't find it along the way, we'll
be too dead to worry about the race.
Also, this cork, what do I
have to do to spin this thing?
Our racers gather at the line,
ready to face the next of
their levers with daring do.
And they're up, the second stage of
the Steel Ball Run has commenced!
Huh?
I'll be damned, Gyro Zeppeli searches
ahead to claim an early lead!
Is he stubborn as a mule or just an idiot?
When I warned him earlier,
was he even listening?
Son of a...
of course I'm going to follow him!
I'm coming with you, dammit!
There's no way!
What on earth is that police thinking?
Not only jumping ahead,
but changing cars, too!
You've got to be kidding me!
Does he mean to skip
the watering holes and
cut straight through the
middle of the desert?
Are you insane, Gyro?
We have 750 miles of sand ahead of us!
Do you have a death wish?
Better not forget, we're still
rivals in this race, you know?
I'm taking the quickest route.
Tag along if you want to.
Not much of a choice.
Somebody will take this shortcut.
Bet you Sandman will be right at home.
Damn it!
Man alive!
Jairo's not the only one
yelling to a certain death!
We've got a handful!
I don't think anyone in their
right mind would take this route!
It's like they're trying
to kill themselves!
We must bid our intrepid racers farewell
for the moment, ladies and gents.
We'll forge ahead as the railway decrees
and await their arrival at the checkpoint.
What's with that guy, huh?
Something's hanging from his ears,
but he's kicking up so much
sand I can't really see.
His saddlecloth number is registered
to a man named Robinson, I think.
He's about 150 horse lengths away.
Hey, Gyro, we started
racing six hours ago.
Are you sure we're heading
in the right direction?
We're 50 miles out from the watering hole.
You didn't make a mistake, did you?
I only ask because that mountain
ahead is pretty specific,
and I don't see it anywhere on the ma -
Yeah, we're good.
Nothing to worry your pretty
little head about, Johnny.
You know, more or less.
Huh?
Did you just mutter more
or less, you charlatan?
What are you all head up about?
Folks are following us, so
clearly we're going the right way.
Probably. Probably?
If we miss the watering hole,
we will literally perish!
Do you actually know
where we are, yes or no?
It's a simple question, Gyro!
Yeah, I know where we are, give or take.
Deserts are kind of vague, okay?
On the topic of knowing stuff,
what about you mastering spin?
Can you spin the cork
like how I taught you yet?
How come you stopped?
Just now, something flew by us.
Gyro, oh my god, your
ear, it's barely... Huh?
What's happening?
Dammit!
My arms all cut up! Up ahead of us!
Whatever's hitting us is
flying in from that way!
That guy!
He started galloping!
He's trying to catch up to us!
Was it him?
Is he the one who ambushed us? Easy, Gyro.
The direction of the attacks is strange.
They came from up ahead of us, right?
We should get behind the rocks for now.
No big movements.
Keep your horse calm.
Whoever's attacking hit
us with cactus needles.
Are you familiar with the desert?
Familiar enough.
Around here, there's a cactus
that shoots out its needles.
It's called a jumping Chil.
When anything gets too close,
it reacts to the vibrations in
the air and fires a barrage.
Damn it.
Jumping chollas all around.
This portion of the desert
looks to be full of them.
Well then, who's at
fault for this debacle?
Is the blame ours for stepping
into a patch of angry cacti?
Or option two?
Did our new friend down there somehow
mount an attack on us with the local flora?
I'm not sure. As I recall,
you have to get pretty close to a jumping
choya to make it shoot its needles.
And he was never in
front of us. Maybe not.
But he has a good motive
to take us out that way.
If the ruling is death by cactus,
he can kill us in plain sight
without earning a penalty for it
So what do we do?
We still don't know if he's the attacker.
Shit, we're sitting ducks
out here in the open!
Time to run for it, Johnny.
Right, let's go!
They're cut.
No way, he cut my reins with needles?
How is he doing this?
Get on your horse, quick!
That guy has got us in his crosshairs!
Leave me, Gyro!
I've got blood in my
eyes, but I can still see!
I said go!
I know we promised to reach the finish
line together, but a race is a race!
Please, you don't need to wait for me!
I'll be right behind you, Gyro, I swear!
So be it.
I'll go on ahead. Good! Hurry!
Except...
lie ahead.
I mean straightforward that bastard!
Gyro!
Your steel balls are
considered weapons, remember?
And we don't have any proof
he's the one attacking us!
Assault another racer without cause, and
they'll kick you out of the steel ball run!
Just go!
Get out of here while you
still can, I'm begging you!
Finish the race with
or without me, please!
In some villages out here, whenever
a dispute would lead to a duel,
they'd chain the loser to a
cactus and leave him for dead?
which he is in no time at all.
Growing up in a place like that,
I learned certain techniques to
keep myself safe in the event of a
fight I filled an eye socket with
insects and claimed the advantage
the air pressure created by their
buzzing wings lets me fire jumping
Chil needles at whatever I desire
and now that I have revealed my secret
technique to you you must die first
place will belong to me and me alone
it sounds like you and I approach the
issue in the same way did you think?
Think I just dropped my balls on accident?
I would never, which means
I dropped them on purpose.
That low hum, I didn't notice it before.
If it's not coming from my
insects, then what's the source?
I may not have the aim of
your little bug friends,
but my spinning balls can
vibrate something fierce.
They travel through the ground
and have got you surrounded.
The crossfire's gonna be brutal.
I'd better find cover.
I didn't do the least little thing to him.
But the cacti sure did.
That ate up more daylight than expected.
Whatcha say, Johnny?
Shall we get back to it?
Yeah.
Let's go!
Don't run away from
the south to the south.
The goal is still long.
Still, ball, run.
Go, go, go, from the town from the town.
I feel like you're hard
to become stronger.
I feel like you're not going to lose.
I'm on your feet from
the south to the south.
I don't care if you don't
care if you don't care.
If you're against the
enemy, you're going to win.
I don't have to compare
it to the other people.
I don't want anyone to find
the path I'm going to go?
Who's the biggest goal? Where are you?
Where are you looking for a dream?
We will be able to do the whole thing.
I've got a few more money.
I'm not going to die like today.
I'm not going to die or die or die.
I'm not going to drive from
the south to the south.
I'll be able to wreck the fast pace.
I'm still going to get to the goal.
Still, ball, run.
Over there, it's a Fool named Robinson.
It doesn't match the print.
I'm looking for a horseshoe with a divot.
That's how I'm gonna find our killer.
But I know I'm close
to tracking them down.
Turns out the horse with the chipped
shoe passed by this ferry way.
Not 30 minutes ago, I reckon.
Thank you.